Very warm welcome to the ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited's Q4
and FY2026 earnings conference call.
From the senior management, we have with
us today Mr. Sanjeev Mantri, MD and CEO
of the company.
Mr. Gopal Balachandran, CFO.
Mr. Anand Singhi, Chief Retail and
Government.
Mr. Girish Nayak, Chief Enterprise AI
and Technology.
Mr. Sandeep Bakhshi,
Chief Corporate Solutions, International
and Bancassurance.
Mr. Gaurav Arora,
Chief Commercial Lines and Motor,
Underwriting and Claims.
And Mr. Girish Sehgal, Chief Health, UW
and Claims, Customer Service and
Operations.
Please note that any statements or
comments made in today's call that may
look like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as the future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from current views
being expressed.
As a reminder, all participants' lines
will be in the listen-only mode and
there will be an opportunity for you to
ask questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during this
conference,
please signal an operator by pressing
star then zero on your touch-tone phone.
Please note that this conference is
being recorded.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjeev Mantri, MD and CEO, ICICI
Lombard General Insurance Limited.
Thank you and over to you, sir.
Thank you.
Good evening to each one of you.
Thank you for joining the earnings
conference call of ICICI Lombard for
quarter four and financial year 2026.
I would like to commence with an
overview of the economic and industry
trends which have shaped the operating
environment over past few months
coupled with insights on our company's
performance and our key initiatives.
Following that, our CFO, Gopal
Balachandran, will take you through the
company's financial performance for
quarter four and financial year 2026.
The quarter gone by has been an eventful
one.
For the first two months, the Indian
economy exhibited continued momentum of
growth from the previous quarter.
Whereas, the month of March 2026 has
seen has been unprecedented in terms of
the geopolitical challenges.
The ongoing conflict in West Asia has
heightened global economic uncertainty
leading to volatility in energy prices
and financial markets.
These external risks could have some
spillover effects on the Indian economy
warranting a measured and watchful
approach.
That being said, India's macroeconomic
fundamentals today are considerably
strong and more resilient than in
previous periods of global stress.
This provides a degree of comfort in our
ability to absorb external shocks,
although we remain mindful of evolving
global conditions.
Let me now dwell upon the ensuing
quarter and the year gone by.
Retail sales of private cars,
two-wheelers and tractors remained
positive for the year.
In accordance with the data reported by
Vahan for financial year 2026, the sales
growth of private car and two-wheeler
stood at healthy 11.9% and 13.2%
respectively.
Pertinently, for H2 2026, the sales
growth of private car and two-wheeler
stood at 17.8 and 21.5 as against 4.6
and 3.2 respectively in H1 2026 led by
GST rationalization.
This continued momentum is also seen in
quarter four 2026 wherein the growth of
private car and two-wheeler stood at a
healthy 16.3 and 24.7% respectively.
Also noteworthy was the fact that
two-wheeler sales surpassed
surpassed their
pre-COVID peak and were at a decadal
high.
Even the sales of commercial vehicle,
this is the data reported by Vahan, have
witnessed a growth of 20.2% in H2 2026
versus 14.4.9%
for H1 2026 and a full year growth of
12.9%.
Given the early trends of numbers
reported by certain banks, credit growth
is expected to be in double digit for
quarter four 2026 with broad-based
expansion across segments. Also, vehicle
vehicle financing continued to be an
important contributor to credit growth
broadly in line with the trends observed
in retail automobile sales.
We believe that the above factors
augment well for the industry in time to
come.
Moving to the regulatory update,
you may be aware that IRDAI has mandated
insurers to prepare and present their
financial statements in accordance with
the applicable IND-AS effective 1st
April 2026. We We view this as a
positive step as the enhanced disclosure
requirements under IND-AS framework will
meaningfully improve transparency and
align the reporting standards of Indian
insurers with global practices.
While the regulator requires insurers to
provide the reporting as per both IND-AS
and Indian GAAP for 2027 and 2028, it
has provided the insurer the option of
seeking forbearance to transitioning the
statutory accounting to IND-AS for the
first year.
We have examined the option provided by
the authority and believe it would be
appropriate to seek the forbearance in
order to ensure that the transition is
executed in a calibrated and
operationally robust manner.
Another important initiative announced
by the authority is the public insurance
registry which is expected to become a
key pillar of India's digital public
infrastructure.
As the framework evolves, PIR has the
potential to support industry growth by
improving penetration, driving
efficiency, elevating customer service,
and also enabling better risk selection
across ecosystem. We believe that over
time it will also
enhance transparency, strengthen trust,
and create enduring benefit for the
policyholder, insurer, and the broader
financial system.
Let me now dwell upon the industry
performance for the year ended March
31st, 2026.
The general insurance industry reported
a GDPI growth of 9.2% for 2026.
Excluding crop and marshal segment, the
gross GDPI growth stood at 13.3% for
2026.
Speaking of the specific segments within
the industry,
the commercial segment reported a growth
of 12.2%
for 2026.
However, if one was to break down this
growth into H1 and H2, the growth was
14.2 and 9.6% respectively.
As one observes, the business witnessed
elevated level of competitive intensity
and pricing pressure, especially in the
fire segment in the second half of the
year leading to muted growth.
The renewal of April 1st, 2026 also are
being reported at a discount to the
previous year reflecting that this trend
is likely to continue for quarter one,
2027 as well.
On the positive side, however, we also
would like to mention that the
the reinsurance renewals for financial
year 2027 have been soft.
The motor segment
growth for the industry stood at 9.2%
for financial year 2026. With the
momentum experienced post the GST
rationalization, the second half of the
year has witnessed improved growth
levels of 10.5 vis-à-vis the first half
which stood at 7.6%.
The health segment, including mass
health, grew by 15.4% for 2026 which
makes it the fastest growing segment for
last five years for from financial year
2022 to 2026.
Within this, the group health line of
business grew at 12.8% for 2026, whereas
the retail health grew growth stood at
19.9% for 2026.
Speaking on the underwriting performance
of the industry, overall the combined
ratio of the industry deteriorated from
113.2%
in nine months financial year 2025 to
119.3
in nine months 2026.
The overall combined ratio for private
players remained relatively flattish for
from 111.2%
for the period nine months 2025 to
111.5%
for the period nine months 2026. Due to
pricing pressure, combined ratio for the
motor line of business continued to
remain elevated at 128.1%
for nine months 2026 vis-à-vis 123.8%
for the period ended nine months 2025.
I will now proceed to present our
company's performance across key
business segments for 2026. The company
reported a growth of 7% in gross
domestic premium income for 2026
compared to the industry growth of 9.2%
for the same period.
ICICI Lombard achieved a growth of 18.2%
and 15.7% in quarter four and H2 2026
respectively against an industry growth
of 10.9 and 11.2% over the same period.
However, excluding the crop and marshal
segment, the company recorded a growth
of 10.2%
and for financial year 2026 while the
industry grew at 13.3% for the same
period.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 5.4% for financial year
2026 as against compared to industry
growth of 12.2% for 2026.
During H1 2026, our growth in commercial
line stood at 6.5%
versus industry growth of 14.2%
versus for H2 2026, the growth level
stood at 3.8%
percent versus industry growth of 9.6%.
Amidst Amidst competitive pressure, we
continue to drive profitable growth
through prudent underwriting and
judicious risk selection through our
multi-channel distribution. We continue
to maintain leadership position in
liability and marine cargo line of
business for financial year 2026.
In motor segment, our growth stood at
7.6% for financial year 2026 as against
industry growth of 9.2% for the same
period. In H1 of 2026, we grew at 2.2%
in the motor segment versus the industry
growth with grew at 7.6%.
However, H2 of 2026, we exceeded the
growth level of industry by 1 and 1/2%
in motor, that is 12% versus the
industry growth of 10.5%.
This momentum was evident in quarter
four of financial year 2026 where we
achieved a growth of 15% with While the
industry grew at 10%.
Our portfolio mix for private car,
two-wheeler, and combined and commercial
vehicle stood at 52.8%, 25.4%,
and 21.8% respectively for financial
year 2026.
In the health segment for 2026, we grew
by 20% as against the industry growth of
15.4%
on a Y by N basis.
For quarter four 2026, the growth stood
at a robust 38.2%
as against the industry growth of 20.5%.
Our retail health business
continued to demonstrate strong growth
of 51.1%
for 2026, significantly outpacing the
industry growth of 19.9%
in the same period.
Consequently, [clears throat]
our market share has improved from 3.3%
in financial year 2025 to 4.1% in
financial year 2026.
For the year, the company has seen a two
X growth in the new retail health
indemnity business sold compared to the
previous year.
Our share of long-term premiums in new
business for retail health stands at
42.1%
for financial year 2021, up from 28.5%
for financial year 2025. This
performance has been driven by our
ongoing product innovation and sustained
investment in strengthening our retail
health health distribution franchise or
retail health
distribution franchise.
For the overall group health portfolio
portfolio, we continue to maintain a
disciplined approach with a focus on
managing the book effectively. The group
health segment recorded a growth of 11%
for financial year 2026 over 2025
with a market share being 8.7% for
financial year 2026.
We have kept a focus on augmenting cash
flows through underlying long-term
business in various line of business.
Our advanced premium in motor insurance
has increased by over 15% in financial
year 2026 versus financial year 2025.
Our market share in advanced premium,
excluding motor share, stands at 12.5%
for financial year 2026, up from 9.6%
for financial year 2025.
Our disciplined focus on profitable
growth has helped us deliver consistent
outcomes over time. While market
fluctuations may impact performance in
individual quarters, our track record
reflects our ability to navigate cycles
and deliver value.
If we analyze the 10-year time horizon
from financial year 2020 2016 to 2025,
it is pertinent to note that the
company's average combined ratio stood
at 102.9%
reflecting sustained underwriting
chances. This would compare favorably
favorably with the industry average of
115.3%
over the same period.
also remains strong.
Over the same 10-year
10-year horizon, we delivered a robust
average realized yield of 8.7%
supported by prudent asset allocation
and effective capital management over
multiple cycles. This in turn has
translated into an healthy average
return on equity of 19.1%
over the 10-year period, which would
compare favorably against the industry
average ROE of 4%.
Reinforcing the strength and resilience
of our overall business model and
consistency of our execution.
Our one at one team philosophy continues
to foster collaboration and operational
excellence,
enabling a unified approach across the
organization.
As a part of this philosophy, we'll now
apprise you of certain key initiatives.
First, I would like to highlight a
strategic capability we have built
in-house, one that materially
strengthens our execution engine. We
call it IL1Force.
IL1Force is an enterprise productivity
platform which has been in operation for
over a year and is used by over 10,000
sales employees. It is on track to
become the single operating platform for
all our 15,000 employees across the
organization.
IL1Force integrates work execution,
performance management, collaboration,
and recognition into a single platform,
simplifying operations, reinforcing
execution discipline, and driving
accountability with real-time
enterprise-wide visibility.
The platform enables structured partner
engagement, task management, and
real-time performance analytics across
the partner life cycle.
Its renewal capability has improved
conversion by 5% while enhanced
engagement with
While
enhanced engagement has doubled partner
participation and expanded market reach.
Notably, in health indemnity, improved
engagement led to a two X increase in
agent activation and a doubling of new
retail business.
Our IL Take Care app, a one-stop
solution for insurance and wellness
needs, achieved 21 million downloads as
of 31st March 2026, reflecting the
growing customer engagement and digital
adoption. The GWP earned from the IL
Take Care app during the period 2026 was
501 5170 million versus the
corresponding premium earning for 2025,
which stood at 2237.2
million.
From a claim intimation perspective, 67%
of the customers now intimate their
health reimbursement claims through the
app while 82% of the claim intimation of
our travel product, Trip Secure Plus,
went through IL Take Care app.
We continue to focus on improving the
service experience of our customers with
a single simplified interface for their
insurance requirements. We continue to
improve our efficiency level in motor
claims, too.
Our preferred partner network serviced
75.5%
of our non-OEM claims for quarter four
2026 respectively, up from 74.1%
for quarter four 2025. For nine months,
we recorded an NPS of 69 for motor
claims.
In the retail segment, 98.8%
of our total claims were paid within 30
days for financial year 2026. For the
nine months 2026, on a count basis, the
number stood at 99.9%
with the corresponding number for the
industry being at 82.1%.
For nine months 2026, we recorded an NPS
of 73 for health claims, demonstrating
strong satisfaction level and
reinforcing our position as a
customer-centric organization.
Our IL Saathi app has further
strengthened our ongoing claims support
for our health customers and our
customer coverage improving by 25% over
the previous year.
As a part of their feedback, 95% of our
customer surveyed rated their experience
as exemplary, highlighting the support
provided during claims processing and
assistance with hospital coordination.
This reaffirms our focus on
best-in-class service to our customers
during the moment that truly matters.
The One at One Call Center initiative
continues to deliver strong momentum in
the company's transition towards a
digital-first do-it-yourself service
model. In March 2026, more than 5 lakh
service engagements, 69% of the total
service engagements were executed
digitally.
Our differentiated service initiatives,
which we have spoken about in previous
earnings calls, have resulted in
increase of our call center NPS to 74 in
quarter four 2026 from 60 in quarter one
2026.
Before I close, the current year marks
an important milestone in the journey of
ICICI Lombard as we enter into our 25th
year of operation.
We would like to take this opportunity
to express our heartfelt gratitude to
all our stake stakeholders who have been
truly who have truly supported us in our
journey so far, and we look forward to
your continued trust, encouragement, and
support in the years ahead.
I will now request Gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for
quarter four and financial year 2026.
Thanks, Sanjeev, and good evening to
each one of you.
I will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the
recently concluded quarter and the full
financial year.
We have uploaded the results
presentation on our website.
You can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers.
With effect from October 1, 2024,
long-term products are accounted on a 1
by n basis as mandated by the regulator
IIDAI.
Please refer our investor presentation
slide number 16 for
the further details on comparison of
financials on a on an n and 1 by n
basis.
It may be noted that all the numbers
that have been speak
1 by n basis unless otherwise mentioned.
On combined ratio,
our combined ratio on an n basis for
FY26 was 102.4%
as against 102.6% in FY25.
For the current year was 103.4
as against 102.8%
in FY25.
Excluding the impact of wage code of
rupees 0.55 billion,
the combined ratio for FY26 stood at
102.1%
and 103.1%
on n basis and 1 by n basis
respectively.
Our combined ratio on an n basis for
quarter four was 100.5
as against 102.1 in quarter four of
FY25.
Our combined ratio on a 1 by n basis for
quarter four current year was 101.2 as
against 102.5 in quarter four of last
year.
On investments,
0.21 billion
as at March 31, 2026 up from rupees
582.96 billion as at December 31, 2025.
Our investment leverage net of
borrowings
was at 3.48 times at March 31, 2026
and at 3.6 times as at December 31,
2025.
Investment income was at rupees 47.42
billion in FY26 as against rupees
42.5 billion in FY25.
On a quarterly basis, investment income
was at rupees 9.85 billion
in Q4 this year as against rupees 8.77
billion in Q4 last year.
During the quarter under review, the
company has recognized we have a policy
on impairment of
investment assets.
Uh basis that, the company has
recognized an impairment on its equity
portfolio investments of rupees
0.49 billion in this quarter for FY26
versus a small write-back that we had of
almost about 3 crores
uh that we had in quarter four of the
last financial year.
Driven by the prevailing market
correction.
Now, coming to profitability,
our profit before tax grew by 10.2% to
rupees 36.59 billion in FY26 as against
rupees 33.21 billion in FY25.
Excluding the impact of the wage code
that I referred earlier of rupees 0.55
billion,
the PBT grew by 11.8% to rupees 37.14
billion in FY26.
Our PBT grew by 7.5% to rupees 7.18
billion in Q4 FY26 as against rupees
6.68 billion in Q4 FY25.
On the profit after tax,
therefore consequently on a 1 by n
basis, the PAT grew by 10.5% to rupees
27.72 billion in FY26 as against rupees
25.08 billion in
FY25.
n basis grew by 12.2% to rupees 28.14
billion in FY26.
On an n basis, PAT grew by 14.1% to
rupees 27.61 billion in FY26 as against
rupees
24.19 billion in FY25.
On an n basis, excluding the impact of
the wage code, the PAT grew by 15.9%
to rupees 28.03 billion in FY26.
Our PAT on a 1 by n basis grew by 7.3%
to 5.47 billion in Q4
this year as against rupees 5.1 billion
in Q4 last year.
Same numbers on an n basis, PAT grew by
15.6% to to rupees 5.39 billion in Q4
FY26 as against
4.66 billion in Q4 FY25.
Coming to return on average equity, our
ROE was 17.8% in FY26 as against 19.1%
in FY25.
Excluding the impact of wage code of
rupees 0.55 billion, the ROE stood at
18.1%
for FY26.
ROE for quarter four current year was at
13.3%
as against 14.5% in Q4 FY25.
Coming to dividend,
the board of directors of the company
has proposed a final dividend of 7 per
share for FY26.
This payment is however subject to
approval of shareholders in the ensuing
general annual general meeting of the
company.
The overall dividend for FY26 including
the above proposed final dividend is
rupees
13.5 per share.
Last year, the overall dividend was
rupees 12.5 per share.
On solvency, we continue to exhibit a
very healthy solvency ratio of
2.67 times at March 31, 2026 as against
2.69 at December 31, 2025, which
continues to be higher than the minimum
regulatory requirement.
The solvency of course was impacted by
roughly about 14 basis points as an
outcome of the mark-to-market loss
position that we had on the equity book
as at March 31, 2026.
As I conclude, I would like to state
that we are aligned with our ethos of
driving profitable growth,
consistent and sustainable value
creation for all our stakeholders
while ensuring that the interest of
policy holders are at the forefront
at all times. I would like to thank you
all for attending this earnings call
and we will now be happy to take
questions that you may have. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
We will now begin the question and
answer session.
Anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on their touch-tone
telephone.
If you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
two.
Participants are requested to please use
handsets while asking a question.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will now wait
for a moment while the question queue
assembles.
Our first question comes from the line
of Supratim Datta from Jefferies. Please
go ahead.
Hello. Um
thanks a lot for the opportunity. My
first question is on the competitive
environment in the industry. Uh there
have been articles recently indicating
that competition in the commercial lines
have been fairly elevated. You indicated
that, you know, the motor lines
combined ratio remains elevated. So, if
you could give us an idea about, you
know, how competitive environment in the
different segments is panning out, that
would be helpful. And is there any
improvement due to now uh the new and
guidelines kicking in? So, that's my
first question. The second question,
coming to the loss ratio side, uh
this year's fourth quarter motor TP loss
ratio has been significantly lower than
what we have seen in the last uh years
in
fourth quarter motor TP loss ratio. So,
just wanted to understand, you know,
what has played out for this uh
significant improvement versus the run
rate that we have seen previously. And
why is the crop loss ratio negative? If
you could give some color on that.
Lastly, on IFRS, Gopal, you know,
wouldn't it be possible for you to give
us some understanding or clarity
regarding, you know, how your PAT under
IFRS would look versus the IGAAP PAT? Um
that would be very helpful. Thank you.
I'll take the second one first. So,
maybe I can take the second and the
third and then maybe I can maybe Sanjeev
can respond to the first one.
Uh
I think on the loss ratio, Supratim, I
think uh
this obviously comes to us every quarter
and I think our response will still
remain the same as in to say that one,
you have to keep looking at motor as a
category as compared to one looking at
separately
motor own damage and third party. That's
one. Second,
I think we would continue to again
request all of you to keep looking at
numbers more on
uh full year basis as compared to let's
say any given quarter.
And just to kind of refresh what we have
been telling the street is I think the
range that we are comfortable on motor
is between 65 to 67.
I think that is the range that we have
maintained and we could have seen for
the full year current year. I think we
ended at roughly about 66.3%.
It's well within that range and hence to
that extent, I think that's the range
that we would be kind of tracking pretty
closely.
Uh so, in that sense, there is nothing
that has kind of changed. Uh if you ask
us has as any of our reserving
philosophy undergone a change, the short
answer is no and we continue to kind of
maintain prudence uh in terms of
maintaining our uh loss reserves. So,
hence uh I think we have to keep looking
at numbers more on uh full year basis as
compared to any given quarters.
So, that's one. Crop, I think again time
and again we have kind of talked about
it because generally again just to kind
of refresh, most of the businesses in
crop get booked around quarter two and
somewhere around quarter three and maybe
early quarter four
for those are typically the two seasons
that largely get exhibited. In our case,
we had predominantly a large exposure on
crop largely from one state of which a
large part of our premium was something
that had got kind of booked roughly
around quarter two of the year.
And as we have said, it obviously takes
time for the season to kind of play out
in terms of actual loss experiences.
And in any in any quarter when you see
that experience play out, then to that
extent obviously and if you recollect
even at the time of booking the
policies, we obviously follow a very
very conservative approach of providing
for almost 100% loss ratio at the time
of writing the risk. And as the actual
experiences play out, obviously to that
extent in case if you see some kind of a
positive change, then to that extent
that gets reflected again in the given
quarter and hence to that extent is why
possibly you are seeing that number in
line with the loss ratio outcomes for
quarter four. Here again, I would
continue to urge that you should again
look at the numbers more on a full year
basis. On a full year basis, it's pretty
much kind of range bound whether you
look at FI25 or whether whether you look
at FI26.
On INDAS, I think
in line with what we are also kind of
put out as a part of the opening
transcript, at this point of time,
given the state at which So, one, if you
ask us is the Now that is Now there is a
definitive
date in so far as transitioning to INDAS
is concerned. So, hence that's a very
very welcome step in so far as the
overall
industry is concerned. I think that's
what rightfully so the regulator has
done it. In terms of
our own transition, I think we do have
We have been working on a plan of action
in terms of getting our processes
internally up and ready so that we are
able to kind of start reporting uh
numbers to all of you
uh whenever we are kind of ready for it.
At this point of time, I think we will
continue to kind of give in line with
what we have done even in the past. We
have been submitting pro forma numbers
for the last two years. So, we will
continue even for 26-27
on a quarterly basis in line with the
requirements. We will continue to submit
INDAS based results to the regulator.
And maybe we will come back to all of
you at an appropriate time
and then we will possibly start talking
about more specifics in terms of the
impact that it does on both the combined
ratios and maybe the return on equity
objectives because those are the two two
things that the market [clears throat]
obviously kind of wants to hear from us.
So, we will come back on that. And maybe
the first point is Also, you know,
just to close out the IFRS part and we
have always said in the past also
that
the year of adoption, there would be a
significant in combined can be in the
range of 300 which is to you know maybe
400 450 basis points. But look, that's
only the accounting part of it. Economic
value over a period of time, it is
expected to converge and have the
same you know value creation for the
company as it happens. So,
So, our stand pretty much remains same
and yes, from next quarter one, we would
end up doing our submission on that
count. With respect to Supratim on the
competitive pressure that is there and
we spoke about that also when we were
giving the overall briefing for the year
that has gone by, yes, it has
intensified on commercial line of
business.
At the same time, the capacity overall
on the reinsurance side was very high
available and we've been able to see to
some extent it's getting negated. Will
this continue? My my own belief is
market forces will play out, but our own
understanding is when we see intensive
competition, the selection has to get
sharper
because it's
Will we compete in the market? Answer is
yes,
but
what we've been able to write and what
we will write, we will be creating
differentiation. If you remember last
year even in
our over quarters, we had said that
there was a marginal loss of market
share for us on the fire side. Purely
was on account of the fact that we will
do what is comfortable and the output is
in some ways here to see. These are all
very exposure driven products and you
have to be cautious of what you pick and
what you don't and we continue to follow
that. There is no overarching worry. We
are very well placed as an institution
in terms of what practices we have to
counter any such measures that come up
in the market and overall insurance
general insurance in particular have
seen
these kind of conduct at multiple levels
and we are well placed about it. On
motor also in a similar vein, yes, the
industry is being
stretched at multiple counts. The
combined ratio which I just spoke about
for the nine months stated at 128,
clearly not a workable one. We continue
to pick and choose and deliver
a result which is differentiated from
the market. It's probably led by on
multiple count distribution and
underwriting practices which
differentiates in own damage as well as
third party which briefly, you know,
Gopal spoke about.
Thank you.
Understood. Thank you. Thank you. Thank
you.
Thank you.
Thank you, Supratim.
Our next question comes from the line of
Prayesh Jain from Motilal Oswal. Please
go ahead.
Yeah, hi everyone.
Two questions from my side. Firstly, you
just wanted to take a view on your
solvency which is like pretty high at
2.7. How do you think that you will
whether you because you've been
generating good profits over the past
few years and in fact from FI22 to FI25
and even now the solvency has been
increasing. So, how do you see you know
whether you can utilize the solvency
better in terms of paying out dividends
or in any other form to kind of because
and unless the growth is really
exceptional we I'm sure that we wouldn't
need that kind of excess solvency on the
balance sheet. That's question number
one. Second, Sanjeev, you know, you've
been talking about motor TP price hike
and you know, we we discussed this in
the last last few calls as well. But
given the trajectory on the motor TP
loss ratios at about 63.2 in FI25 and
63.8 this year for you, do you think
that you know, motor TP price hike can
come in? And my last question is on on
the health insurance front.
Gopal, if you could split up the loss
ratios for retail retail and group.
Yeah. Yeah, so maybe yeah.
So, So, Prayesh,
so the first one I think
I think as a company,
what we have always maintained is
sufficient
margins when it comes to solvency
because
the Indian market is still on solvency
one regulation. I think of course there
is a road map
to maybe eventually transition to risk
based capital which again as what as
what the regulator has rightfully done
on INDAS, I'm sure they would probably
try and do a similar thing even on
transition to risk based capital as
well. So, obviously one will have to
wait and see how that plays out. But
till that point of time, I think the
Indian market continues to be guided by
solvency one which as I said still
mandates capital asked to be maintained
basis the gross exposures that you have
as an entity and hence to that extent
we'll have to be mindful of and prudent
in terms of the levels of solvency that
we carry as an institution. Having said
that, I think
to your point on the last few years, I
think fair observation, but if you see I
think last couple of years in specific,
I think we have been relatively lower
when it comes when it comes to growth.
But that's something that we have
already seen a clear positive reversal
of trends emerging for us.
And with the momentum that that we have
kind of seen, in all fairness, one would
obviously want to kind of make sure that
we are able to kind of get it extended
even as we head into FI27 and the moment
you will see as what you have seen,
let's say even
in the second half of this year, growth
kind of coming back. So, to that extent
obviously one will
look at consuming some part of the
solvency that we have.
And three, our
solvency is also guided by obviously a
mix of what is it that we want to drive
in terms of the growth objective and
two, at the same time make sure that we
are kind of appropriately kind of
rewarding the investors who have kind of
obviously placed their faith in us. And
in that context, I think if you would
have seen historically, we do have a
board governed dividend distribution
policy in place.
On an average, I think what we have been
able to kind of distribute is roughly
about 25% of our PAT. And this year
again as what we had kind of put out in
our opening transcript, they're roughly
about 13 and 1/2 rupees per share for
the full year roughly translates to
almost about 25% of our profit after
tax. So, hence it's obviously it will be
a continued combination of both
rewarding the shareholders appropriately
and at the same time making sure that we
are able to use the capital for
growth. And the three and the third part
as I said, we will obviously kind of
keep a watch on the transition to risk
based capital. So, that's one.
To your point on the breakup for the
health the loss ratio numbers, I think
yeah, thankfully this time the question
has come ahead of time. So, maybe we'll
answer it. So, I think Q4 of last year
this right now I'll give you the numbers
for quarter four employer-employee book.
The last last year Q4, the loss ratio
was uh
98% and this year that number is almost
the same at 98.1%.
On the retail indemnity book, the loss
ratio for Q4 last year was 64.8.
And this year the quarter four, the loss
ratio on the indemnity book is at 57.6.
Now, the same year numbers on a full
year basis, employer-employee book
for last year has been at 97.2.
And this year full year, the
employer-employee book loss ratio stands
at about 91.9.
On the retail indemnity, full year last
year was 67.9.
This year full year is at about 64.6.
So, just that for now to kind of summit
again on the indemnity book, I think the
range that we have spoken about is
between 65 to 70% and that's what we
have been we have been kind of largely
talking through even in the past several
quarters and broadly if you see the
experience that one has seen, the good
part is I think one we have been able to
book a build a book
which is pretty much to our liking and
it has kind of played out both in terms
of growth in market share and also
staying within the loss ratio range.
So those are the responses to the two
questions. Maybe on the motor third
party So yes
I think possibly it's been almost 5
years now since the
industry has
got a hike at the loss ratio at the
industry level as far as motor TP is
concerned is around 85 and thereabouts
which is significantly you know elevated
where we are we have been able to If you
see and Gopal briefly spoke about it we
have to also reconfigure our portfolio
to get aligned and drive the efficiency
which we've been able to reflect.
It does at times leads to a loss and
whenever we end up having discussions
whether individually or collectively
there's so much of you know questioning
as to why has the market share gone down
gone up that is what it takes to
reconfigure
We've also recalibrated our practice in
terms of ground surveillance and doing
what is required to avoid fraud which
probably we would easily say is among
the lowest in the industry. There's no
way we can claim to eliminate it so
there are multiple factors that go about
it. We remain desirous of the fact that
yes the TP hike for the industry is
overdue and
sooner than later that should play out
but
we can only control what is in our in
our hands this one definitely is not and
in line with that we continue to forge
our own understanding and deliberation
to penetrate market in multiple counts
and make it work for us
as a company and
from my industry standpoint sooner than
later we do hope the relief comes
through.
Thank you. Thank you so much. Thank you.
Thanks Suresh.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Sanket Godha from Avendus Spark. Please
go ahead.
Yeah thank you. Thank you for the
opportunity
so my my my first question is is that
last year we we kind of lost market
share in commercial lines
and and given given the market is soft
as you highlighted is it fair to say
that
we we will claw back kind of the market
share in the softer market or we will
remain as cautious as we were last time?
And and in and and in in these lines
just wanted to understand given given
soft market growth outlook
given given
your second half growth is 16%
and maybe crop being a new tendering
tendering
year
how do you see growth of the 16% to
continue for the next year
and any any color if you can give on
that those lines will be very useful.
That's my first question maybe maybe
I'll ask another one later.
Okay
Sanket I think
last year
I'm saying when you say last year it's a
year before the one which you have just
given the result which is financial 25
we were we didn't lose market share we
had gained by 0.1 we had a quarter here
and we missed but overall we had gained.
We were talking about a market share
which is the range of 13.7
which was a year before last this year
we have closed by 0.8 0.7 basis points
lower
and it's driven through multiple
contribution when we meet up personally
for more than happy to Sanket run
through that.
These
that kind of a share that we draw these
fluctuations to ensure that we select
right can happen but
the commercial practice that we have is
very unique in the industry and it's not
driven by what business we are able to
write it's about how we are able to even
manage claims.
There's a significant contribution on
large corporates to mid end to small
honestly speaking from an entity
standpoint we've been we've done a much
more
you know decent job on the large
corporate side and over the last two to
three years which we've been briefing to
you it's been a more distribution led
growth and we've been able to diversify
portfolio in a in a significant manner.
We do we do believe that
we are we have a very significant edge
in the overall practice and we will be
able to have a you know
a reasonable presence as far as
commercial is concerned. I don't want to
jump the gun to say where the market
share will be but we will be a very
relevant player and it's not easy to see
us losing foothold on that on an
overarching basis.
Crop coming into play we will
and yes the market opens up
significantly we are still awaiting the
details in terms of on what contours
this market will open as in when those
guidelines come in
we will be able to comment as to what it
is
but we've always maintained our stand
that crop will be purely on selection
basis of what we feel is appropriate
rather than a targeted segment where
we'll say humko itna karna hi hai you
know that's not the way we look at it.
Do we want to participate? It's a bold
yes.
Do we want to you know chase it? The
answer is no.
We we are very well placed overall
to and we are excited actually in terms
of the opportunity that will present
itself. Our current crop number is
what was there year before last to this
year has virtually halved and
there is some play available for us to
make it count in this year.
Yeah.
Sorry.
Sorry you were saying something but go
ahead please go ahead.
>> No no no no no
sorry sorry sorry when I meant April
last year you lost market share in
commercial lines because you believed
the market was too soft and and if you
are assuming it is too soft again maybe
maybe for a year you caught it up but
but but given April is very strong in
the renewal for for
fire whether whether
whether whether whether it will have any
implication in one queue growth or or
April growth which is which is
significantly very big and and lastly
Yeah yeah Sanket yeah go ahead. Lastly
on crop crop just just wanted to add is
that
whether whether you confined till till
last three years to to one state
maybe I don't know what final controls
will be but but it is fair to say that
you you will be expanding beyond a
particular state in in in the current
year or not broadly broadly that's
that's where you are strategically
thinking in those lines or not is the
point I wanted to check. Yeah yeah yes
yes so so
one state worked out because it was the
line of what you wanted to do. It is not
a plan that will continue to be a one
state for this we will go
wherever it makes
you know
commercial sense and we believe that it
is appropriate and crop obviously can
play out the way it is. We are still
awaiting structure so there is there is
we are open to
whatever that comes up are we to be very
honest on that point. And on the
commercial part in terms of
what you were saying
look the growth of the industry itself
will get impacted and we are we are a
such we are an offshoot of that so
we can do better we can do worse
depending on how it pans out
but overall if you remember in H1
we had a
much bigger loss than what it is with
what happened in H2 so
we've also done what is required so what
cannot get
you know what cannot be acquired through
large corporates we've played out in
distribution has taken its own play but
we are very well entrenched so we should
be fine on the commercial part also
overall as an entity.
Understood so so from growth point of
view given the Sorry to interrupt we
request you to please go ahead.
>> So growth on commercial because of fire
being there the industry itself may have
challenges on growth let me
put this very clearly
but it doesn't mean that
it put us at a significant disadvantage
vis-a-vis anybody else.
It will be probably single digit.
Sorry Sanket just to squeeze in I was
asking that second half our growth was
16% though maybe weak in first half. So
this 16% growth run rate you expect to
continue largely for FY27?
There is there is so much happening all
around that
how do we predict that but yes
Gopal mentioned that very briefly we are
very confident of moving into the
quarter one and quarter two on a
positive note overall. As things stand
yes.
But how does the industry play out
overall
we will have to watch at that.
We also presume that the the tailwinds
has got cleared up with the GST cut
which led to a very robust quarter four
would continue to play out definitely
will be well placed for a growth. We are
excited with that opportunity but we'll
have to wait in terms of how the market
plays out.
Yeah thank you. Okay yeah thanks.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Nitesh from Investec. Please go ahead.
Thanks for the opportunity sir. So my
question is on motor. So in motor in H1
we grew lesser than the market and H2 we
grew faster than the market. So what
drove that and what is the outlook of
our growth vis-a-vis industry growth in
FY27 on on in the motor segment?
Yeah okay so Nitesh I think
yes H2 was better there was also
a significant play that came out on
account of new sales
for the country doing better and there
is no denial in you know there's nothing
which we can say
that we tend to do better when new sales
are
very high and we have seen that new grew
at almost 18.8%
for us with a with 13.4 on the old side.
So,
uh
on the outlook of financial year '27,
um
we'll have to see. We do expect a higher
single-digit growth at the industry
level and if that happens, it would be
again uh
good for us. And another thing which
worked out last year was the growth of
two-wheeler by my When I was talking, I
said that it was at a decadal high in
terms of the overall uh growth that
happened. We've been for last three,
four years we've been saying that we've
not beaten the pre-COVID number on
two-wheelers. That itself is again a big
plus uh overall on the uh motor side. I
think the only thing that I'll just add
to this just to uh what Sanjeev was
saying, I think one of the thing
initiatives that we've been also been
speaking in our earlier calls
is our relentless focus on improving
retentions.
Uh
and uh we will be very again happy to
kind of uh indicate that uh for the full
year,
I think at an aggregate, let's say
company level, a large part of which
will be predominantly, let's say, retail
business lines. I think we have seen an
improvement in our overall retention
numbers go up by almost about 5
percentage points.
Uh so, hence that is something that we
will continue to stay focused on even as
we head into FY '27. So, that will be an
important lever
uh that we would obviously kind of uh
uh work on uh beyond, of course, the
point that Sanjeev made in so far as uh
new vehicle sales is concerned.
So, basically, the growth acceleration
that we have seen is a function of
growth of new vehicle sales going up. Uh
new as well as old. the competitive
intensity reducing and we gaining market
share on a like-to-like basis.
Uh so, yeah. So, new and old and I think
it did sometime in quarter one last year
that we had uh as a company extensively
uh worked on the retention part. A lot
of work was done on multiple counts
uh by us. And that's what Gopal is
referring to when he's saying that we
have a delta of a higher retention of
our customers.
Sure. So, and that So,
uh should we expect Q H2 trend to play
out next year also that we will grow
faster than the industry or
Uh
I think I think let me put it this way.
We we we will we are well placed
overall, but uh there are multiple
factors. See, I mean, if there is a
there is a challenge on the energy, the
uh if uh the Indian mentality moves into
the saving part of it rather than
spending, the motor sales, auto sales,
which probably all of you are well aware
of it, actually ends up getting really
muted. We'll have to see how that part
comes in. Uh
Uh what we would say that
uh the momentum on quarter three to
quarter four and so effectively in
quarter one should play out. Uh I would
say yes, we are going with a very
positive mindset at this point of time.
Sure. Sure. Sure. Uh that's it from my
side.
Thanks. Thanks. Thanks. Thanks.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Avinash Singh with MK Global. Please go
ahead.
Yeah, hi. Uh thanks for the opportunity.
Uh good evening. A couple of questions.
The first one uh a bit I would uh say if
you can
uh clarify my understanding, this 49
crore kind of uh charge that you've
taken for diminution in value of
investment
uh provisions in this quarter, is it
largely driven by the equity for market
fall or bond or kind of
uh both? So, that's one. And second, in
motor TP, of course, you have explained
a lot of things. Uh
now, my question is that, okay, we have
not seen a sort of a price hike, but
what had changed for you that you have
kind of accelerated your growth in CV
segment? Now, typically, from whatever
we hear, it is a CV by and large where
the pricing revision is required and
it's not so profitable. But in Q4, uh it
seems that you have gone uh a lot higher
in terms of, you know, uh that uh CV.
So, what had changed there? What kind of
a strategy is there? And for the full
year, uh around 780 crores of motor
third party is that what I'm reading? Uh
is that number I'm seeing correctly?
Thanks.
The last one is
So, maybe I can take the last one. Uh
so, Avinash, again I again we will keep
saying uh you should keep looking at the
loss ratio range that we have spoken
about for motor as a category, which is
between 65 to 67.
An absolute amount of
uh reserve number that you spoke about,
honestly,
uh in our sense, is something that uh
would not necessarily be a right metric
to kind of track. A better metric will
be to keep looking at the loss ratio
outcome, which is the range that we have
kind of spoken about, between 65 to 67.
Now, the good part is I think uh I think
what has worked for us, I think, is I
think we have seen a clear rebound of
growth
and at the same time we have been able
to maintain the loss ratio expectations
that we have set out. Uh so, hence that
extent I think uh is where we have been
able to deliver both on growth as well
as in so far as the loss outcomes. And
that's something that we are very, very
happy with and we are very, very
positive uh when we kind of head into uh
FY '27. Um and as I said uh in response
to the earlier question, is there any
change in the thought process
of any of our reserving philosophies or
reserving processes? Absolutely no.
We continue to maintain prudence. We
continue to maintain
margins uh for any levels of uncertainty
that we see in any of the book. And more
so in the context of motor third party,
which has got a long tail
uh well, long tail uh periods of loss
development. So, hence to that extent uh
that's in response to the point on motor
third party.
Uh to your first point
uh or to to the on the first question
with respect to the 49 crore uh
diminution in the value of investment, I
think this is what I kind of uh
mentioned even as a part of the opening
uh transcript. Uh we have a policy on
impairment of investments uh that we
kind of have in the context of uh equity
investments specifically and consequent
to what we have seen the market
conditions getting exhibited in quarter
four of this year, we have obviously
evaluated stocks that we hold. And this
is the policy that we have. We have done
an impairment of about 49 crores. All of
this 49 crores is in with respect to the
policy on diminution in the value of
equity investments.
Yeah, okay. So, now the
uh CV growth, I think you're absolutely
right.
Uh it's done better.
But there are, you know, multiple moving
parts. I don't want to get into details.
We can do it probably when we meet up,
Avinash, uh and uh talk about it. Uh
we've done better, but the overall
contribution of CV to the book has still
been ring-fenced at 22%. Uh
you see multiple, you know, things. And
there's one more aspect that the cost of
acquisition that comes into play. And if
we see moderation, we see an
opportunity. We are also scanning the
market, adding new vectors. And
something looks viable, we end up doing
it. We've also created a significant
edge vis-à-vis the market through a
fleet management system, which we are
working for last almost uh you know, 18
to 24 months, and that has also started
giving us some bit of an advantage as to
what we can do in commercial vehicles.
It's it's overall, I think, it's still
coming around. Uh and uh we do believe
that the overall growth in CV market
also for uh H2 was at a reasonable
level, which we have given in the
numbers in the details, which also again
presented us with an opportunity to do
what is required. Uh
overall on the practice side, if you see
where ICICI Lombard is, certainly
private car and two-wheeler is uh our,
you know, our strength. But CV, we
continue to
uh exhibit uh a lot more intensity, but
the outcome used to be portrait
uh for us. And for last
couple of quarters, it's come into play
and I sincerely hope that we'll have a
similar trend going forward next year.
Or this year, rather.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Nishant Chamarty from Kotak. Please go
ahead.
Hi. Uh this is slightly open-ended. Uh
Uh if we the regulator is you know,
looking at uh
uh you know, newer set of guidelines or
commissions, uh you know, probably
capping commissions or differing them,
uh you know, assuming that you know,
this kind of leads to
some amount of tightening. How do you
see this impact on the industry and for
yourselves?
Uh Nishant, I think we've always
maintained, you know,
uh an an environment with uh where the
regulator enforces it. In the past also,
we have said that there are quite a few
players who have sought dispensation or
have not followed the guideline, and
that does not augur well. Any tightening
on a uniform basis across the industry
uh would place ICICI Lombard uh at a
significant advantage uh
because we remain within the limits of
expense of management, and uh if others
fall in place, uh we can only see
uh better time ahead for us as an
industry. The the only thing that
remains is uh it should be practiced uh
across the industry at a uniform basis
on a uniform basis.
And uh So, it's it's a welcome sign
uh if it comes out. Uh we always also
mention the fact that we believe the
expense of management should be on a
single slab basis uh so that there is
clarity of execution, and let the market
forces decide as to what uh works for
each one of them in every single
business line.
So, so what is the latest in terms of,
you know, regulatory engagement on EOM?
Is there any revision expected around
the corner along with this separately?
We can we can only say that uh whatever
is accessed by each one of you is what
we access, and we We for what the
regulator has in mind. We don't want to
do any second guessing, but uh
any tightening on account of that would
be welcomed by us because it puts the
industry in
good path with respect to policy holder
and also for us as an institution.
Got it. Got it. Thank you very much and
all the best.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we will take that as a last question for
today.
I would now like to hand the conference
over to Mr. Sanjeev Mantri for closing
comments.
Over to you, sir.
Uh
thank you so much for joining in.
We look forward to the new financial
with renewed hope. We definitely as a
team
uh been excited as to how we've been
able to close H2 over H1 and more so Q4
over the rest of it.
We are positive in terms of how things
can work out for general insurance
industry at large and with the reforms
that the regulator has put in place,
uh but at the same time we hope that
the world moves to a in a in a much
more, you know, peaceful manner in times
to come. So, thank you so much and all
the best to each one of you for joining
in. Thank you so much. Thank you.
Thank you.
On behalf of ICICI Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited, that
concludes this conference.
Thank you all for joining us. You may
now disconnect your lines.